export const QuizDataSE = [
    {
        question: "What is the purpose of version control in software development??",
        options:[ "Managing project budgets", "Tracking and managing changes to source code", "Defining project requirements", "Designing user interfaces"],
        answer: 2
    },
    {
        question: "Which software development methodology emphasizes iterative development and customer feedback?",
        options:[ "Waterfall" , "Spiral" , "Agile" , "V-Model"],
        answer: 3
    },
    {
        question: "What does the term 'code review' refer to in software engineering?",
        options: ["Writing new code", "Analyzing and evaluating existing code", "Compiling code into machine language", " Debugging code"],
        answer: 2
    },
    {
        question: "Which phase of the software development life cycle (SDLC) involves gathering and analyzing user requirements?",
        options: ["Design", "Implementation", " Testing", "Requirement Analysis"],
        answer:4
    },
    {
        question: "What is the primary function of a version control system like Git?",
        options: ["Managing project schedules", "Tracking changes in source code and coordinating team collaboration", "Designing user interfaces", "Writing technical documentation"],
        answer:2
    },
    {
        question: "Which software development principle promotes breaking down a system into smaller, manageable, and independent components?",
        options: ["Encapsulation", "Abstraction", "Modularity", "Polymorphism"],
        answer:3
    },
    {
        question: "What is the purpose of the Unified Modeling Language (UML) in software engineering?",
        options: ["Writing code", "Creating user interfaces", "Visualizing and documenting system architecture and design", "Executing test cases"],
        answer:3
    },
    {
        question: "In software engineering, what does the term 'bug' refer to?",
        options: ["A feature request", " An unexpected error or flaw in the code", "A programming language", "A user interface design element"],
        answer:2
    },
    {
        question: "What is the role of a Software Development Kit (SDK)?",
        options: ["Managing databases", "Providing tools and libraries for software development on a specific platform", "Writing user documentation", " Defining project requirements"],
        answer:2
    },
    {
        question: "What does the term 'refactoring' mean in software engineering?",
        options: ["Writing new code", "Rewriting existing code to improve its structure and maintainability", " Compiling code into machine language", "Debugging code"],
        answer:1
    }

];